大白鲨
-你叫什么名字来着  -克莉丝
-What's your name again? -Chrissy.
-我们到哪去  -游泳
-Where are we goin'? -Swimming.
慢一点  别跑这么快
Slow up. Slow down some.
我没醉呀  慢点
I'm not drunk. Slow down.
等等  我来了
Wait. I'm coming.
我来了
I'm coming.
我真的追上来了
I'm definitely coming.
停一下
Hold on.
我会游泳
I can swim.
却不会走路也不会脱衣服
I just can't walk or undress myself.
快下水呀
Come on in the water.
别急  别急
Take it easy. Take it easy.
救我
Help me!
我来了  我来了
I'm coming. I'm coming.
好痛
It hurts!
天呀  不要
Oh. My God!
上帝救救我
Please help!
为什么此地总不出太阳
How come the sun didn't use to shine in here?
我们秋天买的房子  现在是夏天
We bought the house in the fall. And this is summer.
去喂喂狗吧
Somebody feed the dogs.
好的
Right.
看到孩子了吗
Do you see the kids?
一定是跑到后院去了
They must be in the backyard.
在艾米提通常说"后院儿"
In Amity you say "yard."
他们在"后院儿"离"车儿"不"远儿"
They're in the "yard". Not too "far" from the "car."
-怎么样  -倒像是纽约客
-How's that? -Like you're from New York.
妈  我流血了  刚刚被吸血鬼咬到
Mom. I got cut. I got hit by a vampire.
你们又去荡秋千了
You were playin' on those swings. Weren't you?
那个秋千很危险  千万别去很危险  我还没修好
Those swings are dangerous. Stay off there. I haven't fixed them yet.
还不至于死
I think you're gonna live.
-这种小伤口算不了什么  -喂
-It's not the prettiest thing I've ever seen. -Hello.
-是的  -我可以游泳吗
-Yes. -Can I go swimmin'?
可以  但先等我把伤口处理好
Let me clean this thing off first.
你通常都怎么做  洗掉还是冲掉
What do they usually do? Wash up or float up? Or what?
留在原地
Keep 'em there.
我一刻钟...
I'll be out in about...
-到二十分钟内赶到好吗  -擦干  去贴个邦迪
-...15, 20 minutes. All right? -Dry you off. Go on. Get a Band-Aid.
我得走了  有人失踪
Got to go. Missing person.
游泳季还不到  根本都还没有人来
Season hasn't started. Nobody's even here yet.
警长  你给我听着  小心点好吗
Listen, Chief... be careful. Will ya?
-这个小镇不必了  -爹地
-In this town? -Hi. Dad.
等我上去
Wait a minute. Let me get on.
艾米提警局
-把杯子还我  -没问题
-I want my cup back! -You'll get it.
再见
Wave goodbye. Bye.
欢迎光临艾米提岛
没人见到她下水
Nobody saw her go into the water?
可能有  我当时昏昏沉沉的
Somebody could've. I was sort of passed out.
-你的意思是她跑开了  -不是
-You mean. She ran out on you? -No, Sir.
她一定是淹死的
She must've drowned.
总之是我向你报的案  对吗
Look. I reported it to you. Didn't I?
-你住在这里  -不是  住在哈特佛
-You live here? -No, Hartford.
我念三一学院  家人住在格尼屈
I go to Trinity. My folks live in Greenwich.
-你家人在这出生的  -没错  但我是本岛人
-Your folks were born here. Right? -I'm an Islander.
家父退休后  他们才搬来
They moved off when my dad retired.
-你也是本岛人吗  -不是  纽约人
-You an Islander? -No, New York City.
你是来度暑假的
You here for the summer?
快走
Come on.
老天
Hold it.
Oh. Jesus.
你今儿个可来的真早
You're up awful early.
警长在里面吗
Is the Chief in there?
警长  你忙什么
Chief, what have you got on?
波莉  若你想工作进行顺利
If this new filing system is to work...
必须把那些旧公文拿走
...you must keep that old stuff off my desk.
-只在桌上放"急件"行吗  -是的  警长
-Just the pending. -Yes, Chief.
很多人打电话来抱怨那家空手道学校
We got a bunch of calls about the Karate school.
那个学校九岁的学生
It seems that the 9-year-olds from the school have been...
劈栏杆来练功
...karate-ing the picket fences.
布洛迪警长办公室  是验尸官打来的
Chief Brody's office. The Medical Inspector.
鲨鱼食人
消防队长要你去讨论国庆日...
The Fire Chief wants you to go over...
帮我列一张全市
I want a list of the water activities that the city fathers...
水上活动的清册
...are planning for today.
韩瑞克  "海滩关闭"的告示牌放哪
Hendricks! Where do we keep the "Beach Closed" signs?
从来没有
We never had any.
我店前有一辆卡车载满了破盘子
There's a truck with New Hampshire plates in front of my store.
叫他先填一份表格
Just have him fill out the form.
先填好再说
Just fill it out.
你看那些孩子  把我的围墙弄成什么样子
Look what the kids did to my fence. Eight and nine-year-olds...
-眼镜  -是的  眼镜
-Glasses? -Yeah. Glasses.
我向你保证  下午再给你电话
I'll call you later in the afternoon. I promise.
艾米提岛欢庆七月四日
这一些货到八月都不能卖
This stuff ain't gonna help me in August.
玩水的人都在六月来
The summer ginks come down here in June.
我订的货你一样也没有
You haven't got one thing on here I ordered.
没有遮阳伞  没有躺椅  没有海滩球
Not a beach umbrella. Not a sun lounger. No beach balls.
如果你们服务再...
If I can't get service...
波莉派我来找你  她说有一批童子军
Polly sent me to tell you that there's a bunch...
在艾佛湾举行游泳比赛
...of Boy Scouts in Avril Bay. Doin' the mile swim for their Merit Badges.
我联络不上  那儿没电话
I couldn't call them in. There's no phones out there.
好吧  你下车
Come on. Get out of there.
把这些拿回办公室  做一些告示牌
Take this stuff back to the office and work on those signs.
"海滩关闭  禁止游泳  艾米提警局"
"Beaches Closed. No Swimming. By order of the Amity P.D."
-让波莉去上油漆  -为什么不让我漆
-What's the matter with my printing? -Let Polly do the printing.
让波莉漆
Let Polly do the printing.
警长  你那里有什么收获吗
Chief Brody! What have you got there?
市长  今早南滩有人  被鲨鱼咬死了
We had a shark attack at South Beach this morning. Mayor.
我得去封闭海滩
Fatal. I have to batten down the beach.
艾尔柏  快呀  笨蛋  手臂抬高点
Albert. Come on. You kook. Keep your arms up.
查理  带我到孩子那边去  好吗
Charlie. Take me out to those kids. Will ya?
你想下令把海滩封闭掉
Martin, You're gonna shut down the beaches on your own authority?
莫非还需要别人的命令
What other authority do I need?
技术上  你需要颁订市民法  或是专人表决通过
You need a civic ordinance or a resolution by the board.
这一套都是照章行事
That's going by the book.
我们其实对你
We're really a little anxious that
这样仓促行事有点顾虑
you're rushing into something serious here.
这是你上任的第一个夏天
This is your first summer. You know.
这句话什么意思
What does that mean?
我真正的意思是艾米提是个避暑胜地
I'm only trying to say that Amity is a summer town.
我们需要赚这笔钱
We need summer dollars.
如果这儿不准游泳
If they can't swim here.
游客会跑到鳕鱼角
They'll be glad to swim at the beaches of Cape Cod...
新汉普顿或长岛
...the Hamptons. Long Island.
也不能冒被鲨鱼咬的危险呀
That doesn't mean we serve them a smorgasbord.
本海域中未曾出现过这种麻烦
But we've never had that kind of trouble in these waters.
那个女孩又是被什么咬死的  船的螺旋桨
What else could've done that? A boat propeller?
我认为...可能是  没错  划船出了意外
I think possibly yes. A boating accident.
你电话上可不是这么对我说的
That's not what you told me over the phone.
我弄错了  报告书上也得修改
I was wrong. We'll have to amend our reports.
-你坚持这种说法  -我坚持
-And you'll stand by that? -I'll stand by that.
只不过是个女生
A summer girl goes swimming.
在海中游远了  累了  渔船开过来...
Swims out a little far. She tires. Fishing boat comes along...
以前也发生过
It's happened before.
我认为你并不了解一般人对这种事情的反应
I don't think you appreciate the reaction people have to these things.
哈利  我了解  我只是照听到的事实采取措施
I appreciate it. I'm just reacting to what I was told.
马丁  群众心里都一样
It's all psychological.
你大喊"梭鱼"  其他人就问"什么"
You yell "Barracuda!" And everybody says. "What?"
你若喊出"鲨鱼"
You yell. "Shark!"...
今年国庆日就满城人心惶惶
...we've got a panic on our hands on the Fourth of July.
好了  送我们回去吧
Okay. You can take us back now.
我要拿救生筏再下水
I'm gonna get my raft and go back out in the water.
我看看你的手指
Let me see your fingers.
亚力克·金特纳  你的手指都泡白了
Alex Kintner. They're beginning to prune.
再让我去玩一下子
Just let me go out a little longer.
-再十分钟  -谢谢
-Just 10 more minutes. -Thanks.
没有岛民  他们都不是岛民
There are no Islanders. None of them are from the island.
真烦
It's just a big bother.
我只想知道一件小事
All I want to know...
我什么时候才能成为岛民
I just want to know one simple thing: When do I get to become an Islander?
艾琳  别想
Ellen. Never. Never.
你不是在此出生  就不是岛民
You're not born here. You're not an Islander. That's it.
别去烦他  马上回来
Don't bother him. Come right back.
马丁  我知道  你在镇上也有一些问题要处理
Martin, I know you got a lot of problems downtown...
不过我家里也出问题  希望你能来处理
...but I've got a couple of problems I wish you'd take care of.
第一件事  我家门口有一堆猫赖着不走
One. I've got some cats parking in front of the house.
还有在办公室旁边的垃圾车
I can't get...
我没法去上班
And that garbage truck next to the office, that's terrible.
因此我想弄一块禁停区  这种事你很容易处理
What I need is a red zone. It's simple. You can take care of it.
-之前你做过  -甜心  请你过来一下好吗
-You've done it before. -Come here a minute, please.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
很好  我很好
Yeah. I'm fine. I'm fine.
是不是小孩子下水令你担心了
Look. If the kids goin' in the water is worrying you...
可以叫他们到沙滩上来玩呀
...they can play out here on the beach.
没关系  让他们去
It's all right. Let them go.
好冷
It's cold.
我们了解你  警长
We know all about you, Chief.
你从不下水吗
You don't go in the water at all, do you?
你那顶帽子真丑  哈利
That's some bad hat, Harry.
布洛迪警长  你太紧张了
Chief Brody, you are uptight.
放松点
Come on.
对呀
That's it.
你认识松饼小子
Oh, do you know the muffin man
松饼小子
The muffin man
提比  提比  提比
Tippet! Tippet! Tippet!
你看见了吗
Did you see that?
血
Blood!
统统上来
Everybody out!
快上来
Get them out!
麦克  上来
Michael. Get out of the water!
亚力克  亚力克
Alex! Alex!
若有能力猎杀该鲨鱼  赏金三千重酬
根本不确定是否有鲨鱼
We don't even know if there's a shark around here.
我无法跟你争辩  也无法跟你谈
I can't argue with you. I can't talk to you.
我要跟金特纳太太谈谈  这已经变成竞赛了
I've got to talk to Mrs. Kintner. This is turning into a contest.
还不只这份"公告"  她还登报悬赏
It's not just the Gazette. She's advertising in out of town papers.
大家都会知道这件事  到会议室  空间比较大
I suggest we move to council chambers where we'll have more room.
我负责这里的安全问题
I'm responsible for public safety here.
那你明天再去看  免得有人受伤
Then go out tomorrow and see that no one gets hurt.
这只是件小事  我尽可能不声张
It's a small story. I'll bury it as deep as I can.
这悬赏会登在杂货广告栏上
The ad is gonna run on the back along with the grocery ads.
请进来
Right in here, please.
请进
Move on in. Please.
我不明白你为何要这样小题大做
Why do you insist on playing the heavy?
我的看法能代表本镇大多数人  不仅是我自己
I have a point of view and it speaks for many of the people here.
并不是因为我有汽车旅馆  你觉得如何
Not only me. Because I have the motel. How do you feel about it?
请安静
Let's have some order.
请各位安静
Let's have some order, please.
有什么特别的问题吗
Any special questions?
那三千悬赏是现金还是支票
Is that $3,000 bounty on the shark in cash or check?
我一点也不觉得  这有什么好笑的
I don't think that's funny. I don't think that's funny at all.
这件事是渔人和金特纳太太间的私事
That's private business between you fishermen and Mrs. Kintner.
马丁  请你移驾  布洛迪警长
Martin. Would you please... Chief Brody.
我想宣布目前的计划
I just want to tell you what we're planning so far.
海滩怎么处理
What about the beaches, Chief?
我们尽快找几位暑期副警长来协助
We're gonna put on the extra summer deputies as soon as possible.
然后在海滩上派员监视
And then we're gonna try and use shark spotters on the beach.
你要不要关闭海滩
Are you going to close the beaches?
是的  要关闭
Yes, we are.
我们还将请海洋研究机构
We're also bringing in some experts
的一些专家来此
from the Oceanographic Institute on the mainland.
只关闭二十四小时
Only 24 hours.
我可没有同意
I didn't agree to that.
只关闭二十四小时
Only 24 hours.
二十四小时等于三星期这么久
24 hours is like three weeks.
你们都认识我
You all know me.
知道我靠什么维生
Know how I earn a livin'.
我亲自去抓那头鲨鱼  不过问题没那么容易
I'll catch this bird for you. It ain't gonna be easy.
是条恶鱼
Bad fish.
不比到池塘抓鳕鱼
Not like goin' down to the pond and chasin' blue gills or tommy-cods.
这条鲨鱼可以吞掉一个人
This shark. Swallow you whole.
只要转转舌头  咽个口水
Shakin'. Tenderizin'.
人就进肚了
Down you go.
我们的动作得快
And we got to do it quick.
别把观光客吓跑
Got to bring back the tourists
让生意正常经营
that'll put your businesses on a payin' basis.
这样做不太容易
But it's not gonna be pleasant.
我估计我这条命  绝不只三千美金
I value my neck a lot more than $3,000.
找到它三千
I'll find him for $3,000.
但抓到要宰  就得要一万
But I'll catch him and kill him for $10,000.
你们得下决心
You got to make up your minds.
想要过好日子就得拿出钱来
Gonna stay alive and ante up...
否则出手太小气  整个冬天就得看天过日子
...gonna play it cheap and be on welfare the whole winter.
我不要有志愿者  也不要有人同行
I don't want no volunteers. I don't want no mates.
这么小的岛上  到处都是船长
There's too many captains on this island.
一万元美金我要自己独吃
$10,000. for me. By myself.
我负责把鲨鱼头  鲨鱼尾  交出来
For that, you get the head, the tail, the whole damn thing.
非常谢谢你  昆特先生
Thank you very much, Mr. Quint.
我们会再商量一下
We'll take it under advisement.
市长先生  警长
Mr. Mayor, Chief...
各位先生女士失陪了
...ladies and gentlemen.
不准游泳  艾米提警局关闭海滩
鲨鱼
微波
侦测系统
天呀  你吓坏我了
Oh. God. You scared me.
艾琳  一般人都不了解鲨鱼
You know, Ellen, people don't even know how old sharks are.
它们已经存在两三千年之久  人们不知道
I mean, if they live 2,000, 3,000 years... They don't know.
够了
Enough.
今晚恐怕你都睡不着了
You're not going to be able to go to sleep tonight.
喝吧
Here. Come on.
谢了
Thanks.
想不想喝个醉胡闹一番
Want to get drunk and fool around?
想呀
Oh, yeah.
麦克真是喜欢他的礼物
Mikey really loves his present.
他在哪
Where is he?
坐在礼物里面
Sitting in it.
老天爷
Good God.
好了  麦克  快上来
All right, Michael, out of the boat.
船绑在防波堤上  我坐在船上
Tied up to the jetties. Sittin' in the boat.
快来帮麦克
I'm helpin' Michael.
-快上来  -爹  再让我多玩一会
-Get out of that boat. -Hi. Dad. Just a little longer. Please?
-明天就是他生日  -我不准他在海里
-It's his birthday tomorrow. -I don't want him on the ocean!
他没在海里  他在船上  他又不会下水
He's not on the ocean. He is in a boat. He's not gonna go in the water.
昨天的事发生过后  他怎敢下水
I don't think he'll go in the water again. After what happened yesterday.
别这么说
Now don't say that.
我不希望发生那种事  你也知道
I don't want that to happen. You know that.
我要他先看看划船的规定方法
I want him to read the boating regulations. The rules...
免得他冒冒失失的就去划船
...before he goes out on his own.
麦克  你有没有听到你爹的话
Michael, did you hear your father?
现在就上来快上来
Out of the water now!
我有点累了  先休息一下  免得有人去报警
I'm tired. Let's stop before someone reports us.
别担心警长住在岛的另一边
Don't worry! The chief lives on the other side of the island.
我划的方向是直的吗
Am I comin' in straight?
别担心  继续划
Don't worry about it. Just keep rowin'.
保佑咱们别空手而归  这是我太太假日要吃的牛肉
We better catch something. This is my wife's holiday roast.
别愁了  三千美金可以买不少牛肉
Don't worry about it. $3,000 buys an awful lot of roast.
快来吃吧
Come and get it.
会被潮水带到外海
The tide's takin' it right out.
我们先回家吧
Can't we go home?
它咬走了
He's takin' it.
咬走了
Go. Go. Go.
查理  听我的话  别往后看
Charlie. Take my word for it. Don't look back. Swim. Charlie. Swim.
快游呀  查理  快呀
Swim, Charlie!
游呀  查理  加油
Come on! To me, boy! Come on, Charlie! Swim!
加油  查理  游过来
Come on, Charlie, keep coming. Keep swimming.
查理  快游呀
Come on, a little more. Atta boy.
我爬不上来
I can't get up.
手给我
Give me your hand. Charlie.
帮我
Help me!
脚上来快点
Get your feet out of the water!
可以回家了吧
Can we go home now?
艾米提海港港务局长
然后丹贺德和查理坐在那儿喘气
So then Denherder and Charlie sat there tryin' to catch their breath...
盘算怎么和查理的太太
...and figure out how to tell Charlie's wife
交代冰箱里牛肉的去向
what happened to her freezer full of meat.
这不好笑  一点都不好笑
That's not funny. That's not funny at all.
金特纳太太一定在《野外》杂志上登广告了
Mrs. Kintner must've put her ad in Field and Stream.
我看来倒像是《国家讯报》
Looks more like The National Enquirer.
行了  停下  停下来  全都停下
All right. Hold it. Hold it. Hold everything.
我说了停下
I said, hold it!
-你好  -你好  小伙子  你好吗
-Hello. -Hello. Back. Young feller. How are you?
你该不会和那些疯子一起出海吧
Say. I hope you're not goin' out with those nuts, are you?
韦塔的船先移开
The Weetock boat's gotta move out first.
你先让开  否则他出不来
You have to move out, or he can't get out at all.
先别张帆  先收起来
Don't raise sail. you're going to luff it.
-船上有桨吗  -有
-You got a paddle on the boat? -I got a paddle.
划出去  警官  等一下
Scull it out of here. Officer, wait a second.
你们有多少人坐那条船
How many guys are you gonna put in that boat?
-只要安全就行了对吗  -那样根本不安全
-Whatever's safe. Right? -Yeah. Well that ain't safe.
小心点  那是炸药
Watch it. That's dynamite.
等一下你想带着去哪
Where are you goin' with that?
我要上船呀
I'm goin' on the boat.
拜托帮我叫那些人下船好吗
Help me get those guys out of the boat.
当然
Sure. Come on.
各位先生
Gentlemen.
警官要我转告你们  船超载了
The officer asked me to tell you that you're overloading that boat.
走开
Go on. Get out of here.
你别管闲事行吗  你在乎个什么劲
You ain't going. What do you care?
你可以告诉我岛上  有没有好的餐厅或旅馆
Can you tell me if there's a good restaurant or hotel here?
一直往前走就有
Yeah, you walk straight ahead.
他们统统会死
They're all gonna die.
波莉你听我说  外面有些路障告示牌
Listen to me. We've got some road block signs outside.
你去找人帮忙
You've got to get somebody to help us.
把告示牌搬到公路上面去
Yeah, get those road block signs out on the highway.
因为来玩得游客太多了  应付不了
Because we've got more people down here than we can handle.
你在那里干嘛他们都是你的人  去跟他们谈
What are you doing? These are your people. Go talk to them.
他们不是  全是来自各州的游客
They aren't mine. They're from all over.
你有没看到停车场里的车牌
You see the plates in the parking lot?
康乃狄克  罗德岛  纽泽西  外面就我一人张罗
Connecticut, Rhode Island, New Jersey... I'm all by myself out there.
不是有人来支援吗
What happened to the extra help?
在国庆日前就只有你跟我两人
That's not until the Fourth of July.
你知道那艘船上的八个人吗
You know those guys in that fan-tail launch out there?
他们一个也别想活着上岸
None of them will get out of the harbor alive.
我就是和你谈这个问题  你认识他们  快去谈
That's what I'm saying. You know their names. Talk to those clowns.
今天每个人好像都很开心
Everyone seems to be having a good time.
波莉  我再回电话给你
Tell me about it. I'll get back to you.
那里能找到布洛迪警长
Could you tell me how I could find Chief Brody?
-你是谁  -麦特·胡柏
-Who are you? -Matt Hooper.
海洋研究学院派来的
I'm from the Oceanographic Institute.
老天爷  我们就是找你
For Christ sakes. You're the guy we called. I'm Brody.
-我就是布洛迪  -幸会
-I'm glad to meet you. -Me, too.
我知道你目前很忙
I know you got a lot on your hands right now.
有何事需要效劳的
What can we do for you?
我想最好先
The best thing for me to do is...
看看被害人的肢体  那位海滩上的女孩
...to see the remains of the first victim, the girl on the beach.
-行  跟我来就行  好吗  -好的
-Okay. Fine. Just bear with me. Will ya? -Sure.
等我们把那些小混帐赶到海岩堆上时
Wait'll we get them silly bastards down in that rock pile.
他们会找到点乐子
There'll be some fun.
他们会后悔自己的老爹娶了自己的老妈
They'll wish their fathers had never met their mothers...
到时再看看他们伤着心  从石头中挖尸体吧
...when they start diggin' the bottoms out and slammin' into them rocks.
快点回去  该死的傻瓜
Get away from there. You goddamn fool!
你们是怎么回事  你们这帮疯子  想给给我们找麻烦
What's the matter with you? You want to swamp us. You crazy son of a bitch?
那些人在干什么
What are these guys doin' out here?
告诉我们  他们在干嘛
What are they doin' back there?
-他们在放饵  -这算哪门子事
-They're chummin' right now. -What is that?
他们在吸引鲨鱼
They're tracking the shark now.
三千元除以四是多少
$3,000 divided four ways is what?
让胡柏先生看看那名受害者
Let's show Mr. Hooper our accident.
受害者名叫克莉丝·华肯斯
Victim identified as Christine Watkins.
-白种人女性  -这是我们调查的结果
-Female Caucasian. -And here's the way we have it.
可能是撞船事件
Probable boating accident.
死者的高度和体重
The height and weight of the victim
只能由其部份残肢中预估
can only be estimated from the partial remains.
躯干由胸腔部份分割成段
The torso has been severed in mid-thorax.
内脏器官都没有留下  可以给我杯水吗
There are no major organs remaining. May I have a glass of water?
右臂被咬断
The right arm has been severed above the elbow with massive tissue loss...
上肘处大肌块不见
...in the upper musculature.
非常谢谢
Thank you very much.
部份无肌骨骼残存  这不是船只意外造成的
Partially denuded bone remaining. This was no boat accident.
你有没有通知海岸巡逻队
Did you notify the Coast Guard about this?
没有  这种事管辖权属于本县
No. It was only local jurisdiction.
左臂  头  肩膀
The left arm, head, the shoulders,
胸骨和肋骨都已断裂
sternum and portions of the rib cage are intact.
不要抽烟  谢谢你
Do not smoke in here, thank you very much.
情形就是如此
This is what happens.
情况显示
Indicates the non-frenzy feeding of a large squalus. Possibly longimanus...
大型巨齿动物
...or isurus glaucus.
大块肌肉不见  影响了
The amount of tissue loss
细部分析工作
prevents any detailed analysis...
不过攻击的巨齿动物
...however. The attacking squalus must be larger...
显然比海中任何动物体型都大
...than any normal squalus found in these waters.
你有没下水去查看过海域
Didn't you get a boat and check these waters?
这根本不是船只意外
This is not a boat accident.
既不是螺旋桨  也不是暗礁
And it wasn't any propeller. It wasn't any coral reef.
更不是杀人狂
And it wasn't Jack the Ripper.
是鲨鱼
It was a shark.
新闻送到美联社和合众社  先在本州刊出
I wanna go AP and UPI. I wanna get on the state wire services.
然后交由波士顿方面做全国版刊登
See if Boston'll pick it up and go national.
通知纽约的戴夫·艾斯拉转告他欠我一次人情
Call Dave Axelrod in New York and tell him he owes me a favor.
我要拍一张全体合照鱼也包括在里面好吗
This is the shot I want with everybody and the fish in it.
请各位集合一下
Guys, could we please get organized?
我要拍一张新闻照
I want to get a picture for the paper.
-请各位...-是班·加德纳抓的
-Now, can we just have the... -Ben Gardner get this?
不是  我们抓的
No, We caught it.
恭喜
Congratulations!
很棒吧
It's a beauty. Eh?
我要拍一张新闻照  请各位别挡路
I need a picture for the paper. Clear out of the way. Please.
我只拍抓到鲨鱼的人  请别挡着好吗
Just the guys that caught the fish. Open it up a little bit.
我要拍渔人和鲨鱼的合照
I want to get a picture of the guy with the fish.
我要拍张新闻照  请你把告示牌举起来
I need a picture for the paper. Could we get the sign please?
蹲下  像高中一样
Kneel down, just like in high school.
一脚蹲着  一脚往前
One row kneeling, one row standing.
走开
Come on, just get out of the way.
年轻人  请你出去好吗
Young fella, could you step out of the picture?
把东西一起拿走
Take your rake with you.
-我们准备好了  -谢谢你
-We're ready. -Thank you.
请你拍一张好吗
Can you get that, please.
怎么样
How's that?
赖利  你不会相信的
Larry. You won't believe it.
这是什么鲨
What kind of a shark is that?
不知道  依我看是灰鲨
I don't know. I think it's a mako.
好深的喉咙
It's got a deep throat, Frank.
但它究竟是哪一种鲨鱼
Yeah, but what kind? What kind of shark?
虎鲨
Tiger shark.
你说什么
A what?
总算松口气了
We can start breathing again.
-班可拍了不少新闻照  -这还用说
-Is Ben getting plenty of pictures? -You bet he is.
-你说什么口径不够大  -这张嘴可真大
-What is this bite radius crap? -That is a big mouth.
没人阻止你把头插进去
You stuff your friggin' head in there man.
看看它会不会吃人
And find out if it's a man-eater.
我是说有可能不是
All I'm saying is that it may not be the shark.
口径不对
It's just a slight...
我为你介绍麦特  这位是赖利·彭恩市长
I want you to meet Matt. This is Larry Vaughn, our Mayor.
-麦特是海洋研究学院派来的  -很高兴认识你
-Matt's from the Oceanographic Institute. -Nice to meet you.
真令人兴奋  市长
Terrific, huh, Mayor?
马丁  海中有很多种类的鲨鱼
There are all kinds of sharks in the waters.
榔头鲨  白头鲨  蓝鄂鲨  虎鲨...
Hammerheads, White tips, Blues, Makos...
那些人抓的鲨鱼  很可能是...
And the chances that these bozos got the exact shark...
海里这种鲨鱼可是很少见
There are no other sharks like this here.
马丁  百分之一
It's 100 to 1.
我不否定是这条鲨鱼  也许是的
I'm not saying that this is not the shark. It probably is, Martin.
海中很少见食人鲨
It's a man-eater. It's extremely rare for these waters.
该鲨鱼的口径
The fact is, the bite radius on this animal is different...
与死者身上的伤口不符
...than the wounds on the victim.
我想要再确定  你也希望如此
I want to be sure. You want to be sure.
我们都这样希望  是吗  我要做一个简单的实验
We all want to be sure. Okay? What I want to do is very simple.
鲨鱼的消化过程相当缓慢  我们先把鱼肚剖开
The digestive system of this animal is very very slow. Let's cut it open.
它在二十四小时之内吃的东西一定还留在胃内
Whatever it's eaten in the last 24 hours...
然后我们就可以确定了
...is bound to still be in there. And then we'll be sure.
要弄清楚只有这个法子
It may be the only way to confirm it.
先生  头脑弄清楚
Look, fellas let's be reasonable.
此时此地
This is not the time or the place...
不适合你表演解剖技术
...to perform some kind of a half-assed autopsy on a fish.
我也不会站在这里
I am not going to stand here and see that thing cut open...
眼睁睁的看着那个孩子的尸体满地都是
...and see that little Kintner boy spill out all over the dock.
警长
Chief Brody?
我刚才知道
I just found out...
有个女孩子上星期死在海里
...that a girl got killed here last week.
而你早就知道
And you knew it.
你明明知道海里有鲨鱼
You knew there was a shark out there.
你明明知道有危险
You knew it was dangerous.
而你却不阻止大伙去游泳
But you let people go swimming anyway.
这些事情你早就知道了
You knew all those things...
而我儿子已经死了
...but still my boy is dead now.
你都无能为力
And there's nothing you can do about it.
我儿子已经死了
My boy is dead.
我要你知道这件事
I wanted you to know that.
对不起  马丁  她错了
I'm sorry, Martin, she's wrong.
她没错
No, she's not.
好了  各位
All right. Fellas...
快把这只狗杂碎割下来免得弄得全海滩臭气冲天
...let's cut this ugly son of a bitch down before it stinks up the island.
哈维  你和卡尔明天把它丢掉
Harve, you and Carl take it out tomorrow and dump it in the drink.
过来一下
Come here.
吻我一下
Give us a kiss.
为什么
Why?
因为我需要
Because I need it.
你走吧
Get out of here.
门开着  我可以进去吗
The door was open. Mind if I come in?
-我是麦特·胡柏  -你好  我是艾琳·布洛迪
-I'm Matt Hooper. -Oh, hi. Ellen Brody.
你先生在家  我很希望和他谈谈
Your husband's home? I'd really like to talk to him.
是的  我也想
Yes, so would I.
请进  要不要喝杯咖啡
Can I get you some coffee?
-不  谢谢  -有酒呀  真好
-No, nothing, thank you. -Wine, how nice.
你今天还好吗
How was your day?
好极了
Swell.
我带了红白各一瓶  不知道你喜欢哪一种
I got red and white. I didn't know what you'd be serving.
太好了
That's nice.
这个有人吃吗
Is anyone eating this?
没有
No.
我先生说你专研究鲨鱼
My husband tells me you're in sharks.
对不起  是的  不过我没听别人这样子说法
Excuse me. Yes, I've never heard it quite put that way.
的确是如此我爱鲨鱼
But yes, I am. I love sharks.
-你爱鲨鱼  -是的  我爱鲨鱼
-You love sharks? -Yeah, I love them.
我十二岁那年  父亲送我一艘船
When I was 12 years old. My father got me a boat.
我到鳕鱼角钓鱼
And I went fishing off of Cape Cod.
我用鲷鱼做饵一下子就钓了
I hooked a scup and as I was reeling it in...
一条四英尺半的小鲨鱼
...I hooked a four and a half foot baby thresher shark...
它正在咬我的船
...who proceeded to eat my boat.
它咬我的桨  钩子  还有我的坐垫
He ate my oar, hooks, and my seat cushions.
把我从船上挤下了海  我吓得半死
He turned an inboard into an outboard. Scared me to death...
拼命游上岸去
...and I swam back to shore.
到了海滩之后  转过头一看
When I was on the beach...
我的船已经被咬成两半
...I turned around and I saw my boat being taken apart.
自从那件事之后  我就开始研究鲨鱼
Ever since then. I have been studying sharks...
所以我明天要回研究所去
...and that's why I'm gonna go to the Institute tomorrow...
告诉他们此地有鲨鱼问题
...and tell them that you still have a shark problem here.
-你为何要告诉他们  -抱歉
-Why do you have to tell them that? -I'm sorry. I thought that...
你不是说已经把鲨鱼抓起来了吗
You told me the shark was caught.
我在新闻广播上也听到  岛角电台说的
I heard it on the news. I heard it on the Cape station.
他们是抓了一条鲨鱼  但不是那条鲨鱼
They caught a shark. Not the shark.
不是咬死克莉丝那一条
Not the shark that killed Chrissy Watkins.
可能也不是咬死小男孩的那一条
And probably not the shark that killed the little boy.
我本来想解剖鲨鱼来证明...
Which I wanted to prove by cutting the shark open...
别倒那么多...算了  没关系
You may want to let that breathe... Nothing.
你知道
You know.
明天我一走全岛就剩下你一个明智的人了
You'll be the only rational man left on this island after I leave tomorrow.
你要去哪里
Where are you going?
我要去欧罗拉
I am going on the Aurora.
欧罗拉是什么
The Aurora? What is that?
是一座海上避难所  患了鲨瘾的人去的地方
It's a floating asylum for shark addicts.
纯粹做研究工作  在海上已经十八个月了
It's pure research, 18 months at sea.
马丁讨厌船
Martin hates boats.
马丁讨厌海水
Martin hates water.
我们搭渡船到本土时他都坐在车内
Martin sits in his car when we go on the ferry to the mainland.
我想是和小时候有关
I guess it's a childhood thing.
医学上有个名称不是吗
There's a clinical name for it, isn't there?
惧溺症
Drowning.
据说大多数的人是在水深三英尺处
Is it true that most people get attacked by sharks in...
离岸10英尺远遭鲨鱼攻击  是真的吗
...three feet of water about 10 feet from the beach?
是的
Yeah.
人把下海游泳作为消遣之前
And before people started to swim for recreation...
就有很多鲨鱼攻击事件
...I mean before sharks knew what they were missing...
只不过是没有记录而已
...that a lot of these attacks weren't reported?
没错
That's right.
-那条独来独往的鲨鱼  -恶棍
-Now this shark that swims alone. -What's it called? Rogue.
恶棍  是的
Rogue. Yeah.
它本来在一个食物充足
Now. This guy...
的海域游泳  直到食物溃乏的时候  对吗
...he keeps swimmin' around in a place where the feeding is good...
这叫做领域性
...until the food supply is gone. Right? -That's called territoriality.
我很同意这种理论
It's just a theory that I happen to agree with.
那我们再喝一杯之后就去把鲨鱼肚子剖开
Then why don't we have one more drink and go down and cut that shark open?
你能做到吗
Can you do that?
我什么都能做  我是警长呀
I can do anything. I'm the Chief of Police.
我们先由食道开始
We start in the alimentary canal...
把胃袋给剖开
...open the digestive tract.
-正如我所料的  -什么
-Just like I thought. -What?
是由南方的海域中  随着暖流游来的
Came up from the Gulf Stream from southern waters.
路易斯安那
-它该不会吃汽车吧  -不  虎鲨像垃圾桶
-He didn't eat a car, did he? -No.
无所不吃
Tiger shark's like a garbage can. It'll eat anything.
也许是人由河中倒入的
Somebody probably threw that in the river.
就只有这些
That's it.
我得通知市长  关闭海滩
I've got to close the beach. Call the Mayor.
另外那条更麻烦
You got a bigger problem than that.
海中还有一条更大的
You still got a hell of a fish out there...
嘴巴至少有这么大
...with a mouth about this big.
明早我怎么说服大家
How do we confirm that by morning?
如果它是恶棍  如果领域性是真的
If he is a rogue. And there's any truth to territoriality at all...
我们便可在南滩和史考特岬角之间找到它
...we could spot him between Cape Scott and South Beach.
-你去哪  -我现在就去找它
-Where're you going? -To find him.
-它是夜食者  -你要出海
-He's a night feeder. -On the water?
难道在陆地上找得到鲨鱼吗
We're not gonna find him on the land.
但我也不会醉得坐小船去
I'm not drunk enough to go on a boat.
-你得去  -不去
-Yes. You are. -No. I'm not!
-我做不到  -你能
-I can't do that. -Yes. You can.
纽约的犯罪率真惊人
I'm tellin' you. The crime rate in New York'll kill ya.
问题层出不穷
There's so many problems.
让人有一种无力感
You never feel like you're accomplishing anything.
抢劫  杀人  偷窃
Violence, Rip-offs, Muggings.
孩子不能离家  上学得有人陪
The kids can't leave the house. You've got to walk them to school.
但在艾米提镇上情况就不同了
But in Amity. One man can make a difference.
二十五年以来  从未发生过凶杀案
In 25 years, there's never been a shooting or a murder in this town.
真好想不想吃脆饼
No kidding? Want a pretzel?
这是什么地方
Where are we?
就在鲨鱼猎食的地方
We're right in the stretch where he's been feeding.
这玩意晚上能看节目吗
Can you get the Late Show on this thing?
不行  这是闭路电视
No, it's a closed circuit TV system.
船头船尾各有台水下摄影机
I have underwater cameras fore and aft.
这些玩意都是谁花钱买的  政府还是研究院
Who pays for all this stuff? The Government? The Institute?
这玩意花不少钱
This stuff cost a lot of money.
大部分都是我自己买的
I paid for this mostly myself, actually.
开玩笑
You're kidding.
没有
No.
-你有钱  -是的
-You rich? -Yeah.
多有钱
How much?
你指我个人还是家族
Personally or the whole family?
这种说法不合逻辑
Doesn't make any sense. They pay a guy like you to watch sharks?
家人会花钱买这东西让你去看鲨鱼
It doesn't make sense for a guy
对一个讨厌海的人住在岛上也不合情理
who hates the water to live on an island. Either.
从海上看才觉得这是座岛
It's only an island if you look at it from the water.
这么说的确有些道理
That makes a lot of sense.
那玩意是干什么的
What is that thing doing?
那是追踪鱼用的
It's a fish finder.
可能是一群鲭鱼之类的
It's probably just a school of mackerel or something. All clumped together.
等一下
Wait a minute.
-还有别的东西  -是什么
-There's somethin' else out there. -What is it?
在南西南一百码处
About 100 yards, south, southwest.
-班·加德纳的船  -你认识他
-That's Ben Gardner's boat. -You know him?
它被撞烂了  当然认识  他是渔人
It's all banged up. Sure I know him. He's a fisherman.
怎么回事
What happened?
马丁  我得过去查查看
Martin, I got to go down there and check their hull.
我们把船拉过来再说好了
Wait. Why don't we just tow it in?
我会的  但我得先检查一下
We will. I just got to check something out.
往船上照
Keep the lights going.
拖过来算了
Let's tow it in.
别担心  不会出事的
Don't worry, Martin. Nothing's gonna happen.
你不在的时候我怎么办
What am I supposed to do while you're gone?
什么事也别做  别碰任何仪器
Nothing. Absolutely nothing. Don't touch any of the equipment.
两分钟后就回来
I'll be back in two minutes.
是一条大白鲨
This is a great white, Larry. A big one.
任何鲨鱼专家都会说  它是杀人凶手
Any shark expert in the world will tell you it's a killer.
食人兽
It's a man-eater.
大白鲨以艾米提岛附近做为它活动领域
A great white shark has staked a claim in the waters off Amity Island.
只要海中还有食物它就会继续在此地出没
He'll continue to feed here as long as there's food in the water.
很难预料它会怎么做
There's no limit to what he'll do.
已经发生过三次意外  一星期之内两人丧生
We've had three incidents. Two people killed in a week.
这种事还会再有  以前就发生过了  泽西海滩
It'll happen again. It happened before. The Jersey beach.
-在1916年  -共有五个人冲浪时被咬死
-1916. -Five people were killed...
-前后一星期  -你告诉他游泳的事
-In one week. -Tell him about the swimmers.
鲨鱼会受到某种拨水声或活动的吸引前来
A shark is attracted to the exact kind of splashing and activity...
游泳时一定会发生
...that occurs whenever people swim. You can't avoid it.
如果你在国庆日开放海水海滩
If you open the beaches on the Fourth of July...
就等于摇铃开饭一样
...it's like ringing the dinner bell.
彭恩先生
Look, Mr. Vaughn
我在船壳上拔出一颗玻璃碎片般大的鲨牙
I pulled a tooth. The size of a shot glass. Out of a boat out there.
-就是大白鲨的牙齿  -加德纳的船全被咬烂了
-It was the tooth of a great white. -It was Gardner's boat all chewed up.
我帮忙拖回来的  你真该看看才对
I helped tow it. You should've seen it.
牙齿在哪  你见过吗  布洛迪
Where is that tooth? Did you see it, Brody?
-我没见过  他回来时掉了  -我跌了一跤
-I didn't see it. -He dropped it on the way in. -I had an accident.
你说鲨鱼叫什么名字来着
And what did you say the name of this shark is?
是巨鲨中的巨鲨  叫做大白鲨
It's a carcharodon carcharias. It's a great white.
但你没拿牙齿回来
You don't have the tooth?
我们镇上的收入全靠观光客
We depend on the summer people for our lives...
你不会有夏天  除非你处理好这个问题
You are not gonna have a summer unless you deal with this problem.
我们不仅要关闭海滩  还得雇人来杀鲨鱼
We have to close the beaches. And hire somebody to kill the shark!
我们得通知海岸巡逻队
We have to tell the Coast Guard.
你得跟鲨鱼研究所联络
You'll have to contact the Shark Research Panel.
你要警告整个港口
You'll have to ring this entire harbor.
你们都不了解这个问题
I don't think either one of you are familiar with our problems.
我了解这个问题的所在
I know that you are going to ignore...
依我看如果鲨鱼不咬你的话  你根本不会重视这个问题
...this problem until it swims up and bites you on the ass!
等一下  这问题有两种解决方法
Wait a second. There are two ways to deal with this.
一者是把鲨鱼给杀了  一者是切断它的食物源
You're either gonna kill this animal, or cut off it's food supply.
我们非关闭海滩不可
We have to close the beaches.
欢迎光临艾米提岛  救命啊有鲨鱼
布洛迪  病态的粗俗文化
Brody? Sick vandalism.
这简直刻意地混淆了大众视听
That is a deliberate mutilation of a public service message.
我要你把那些画匠抓起来
I want those little paint-happy bastards caught...
吊死
...and hung up by their Buster-Browns.
可以了  再见
That's it. Goodbye.
我可不想浪费时间和一个将要当鲨鱼午餐的人胡扯
I won't waste my time arguing with a man who's lining up to be a hot lunch.
请你别这么做
Don't do this.
彭恩先生
Mr. Vaughn.
我们面对的是一具巨型的
What we are dealing with here is a perfect engine.
食人机器  这真是进化的奇迹
An eating machine. It's really a miracle of evolution.
这种机器整天只会游泳
All this machine does is swim and eat,
吃人  并制造小鲨鱼  如此而已
and make little sharks. And that's all.
你为什么不仔细瞧瞧这个招牌
Now, why don't you take a long, close look at this sign.
-这些东西的比例倒是正确的  -你就是喜欢求证炫耀
-Those proportions are correct. -You'd love to prove that.
想登上国家地理杂志
Get your name into the National Geographic.
如果我们现在就想办法  八月份还来得及开放
Larry. If we make an effort today. We might be able to save August.
八月
August? For Christ sake.
拜托你明天就是国庆日
Tomorrow's the Fourth of July.
我们要开放营业
And we will be open for business.
从来没有一个这么好的夏天
This will be the best summer we've ever had.
如果你们关心海滩的事
If you are concerned about the beaches do what you have to.
就尽量让游客安全
To make them safe.
但海滩非在周末开放不可
But those beaches will be open for this weekend.
载客处
你告诉我准备派多少人手给我
I want to know how many men you're going to send.
我没有理由去布里斯本
I don't need to come to Brisbane...
此地就出现一条大白鲨
...when I have a great white shark right here.
此地需要人来保护游泳区
We need men to patrol the swimming area.
有枪有船的人我们都用得到
We've got to have help. Anybody with a gun or a boat.
星期一
Monday!
密西根只适合看白老鼠
Is Chief Federal Officer Feldman there?
什么就是那留平头的小个子
He's the little guy with a crew cut.
接线生  岛上有电话吗
Operator, isn't there a phone on the island?
请帮我接好吗
Could you connect me, please?
快杀死它
Come on, get him!
布洛迪呼叫葛加  你听到了吗
Brody to Gotcha. Do you read me?
本土电视的史考特来了
The guys from the TV station on the mainland are here.
好的  我待会去找他
All right. I'll get to them later.
布洛迪呼叫史卡巴  请回答
Brody to Scutbucket. Please come in.
布洛迪呼叫戴西  你听到了吗
Brody to Daisy. Do you read me?
美妙的旋律  你听到了吗请回答  完毕
Fascinating Rhythm, do you read me? Come in, Hooper.
-你看到什么状况  -什么也没看到  马丁
-What do you see? -Nothing here. Martin.
声纳上也没消息
And nothing on sonar.
艾米提岛素以空气清晰  海水洁净
Amity Island has long been known for it's clean air. Clear water...
和美丽的白沙滩闻名全国
...beautiful white sand beaches.
然而近日来
But in recent days...
这个美丽的避暑胜地上笼罩着一片阴影
...a cloud has appeared on the horizon of this beautiful resort community.
人人恐惧着一条食人的大白鲨
A cloud in the shape of a killer shark.
露天体育场办得很好  外面湿气很重
That is very shocking in the outfield.
二坏一好  跑者在一三垒
Two balls, one strike, runners at first and third...
打击出去  飞跃球  左外野
Fly ball, deep left field.
泰瑞回来
Jerry Christian goes back,
警告跑到  靠近墙边  出界
running back near the wall
三垒被刺杀  他进来...
and he takes it for the out.
-赖利  -你怎么没下水
-Hi, Larry. -Why aren't you in the water?
我刚擦了防晒油  我想晒一点...
I just put some sun tan lotion on, and I'm trying to absorb some...
没人下海呀
Nobody's going in.
拜托你下去玩玩
Please, get in the water.
麦克  你来一下
Mike, come here.
麦克  帮我个忙好吗
Do me a favor. Will you?
你和别人带着船到湾里去玩好吗
You and the other guys take the boat and put it in the pond instead.
水湾是给老太太玩的
The pond's for old ladies.
我知道是老太太玩的就算你帮老爸的忙
I know it's for the old ladies, but just do it for the old man.
怎么样  拜托
Please?
-好吧  -谢谢
-All right. -Thanks.
我看着乔了
I've got Sean.
麦克  等等
Michael, wait!
麦克  我不喜欢你
Michael, I don't like you no more.
我能忍受哈利
I can stand Harry, you know...
戴西  我是韩力克
Daisy, this is Hendricks.
你有状况吗  我看到一个黑影
Anything? Thought I saw a shadow. Over.
韩力克  我是戴西  虚惊一场  我没看到任何异状
Hendricks, this is Daisy here. I don't see anything.
警报错误  可能是反光
False alarm. Must be this glare.
我很高兴有此机会  再一次强调
I'm pleased and happy to repeat the news that we have...
我们已经将咬伤游客的大鱼给杀死了
...caught and killed a large predator that supposedly injured some bathers.
各位看  今天天气很好
As you see. It's a beautiful day.
海滩也开放  游客都玩得很开心
The beaches are open, and people are having a wonderful time.
众人皆知  艾米提热诚地欢迎所有人
"Amity." as you know. Means "friendship."
我的
My...
天呀
...God!
老天  鲨鱼鳍出水了  350方位
Jesus Christ! Fin! Shark! 350!
赶紧回来  紧急呼叫
Get in there as fast as you can! Red one.
快把游客叫上岸  鲨鱼进海湾了
Martin, get them the hell out of the water.
别吹哨子  别吹哨子
No whistles! No whistles!
所有游客立刻上岸
Everybody please, get out of the water.
所有游客立刻上岸  让后面的上来
Everybody out of the water.
-快上岸  -到安全的地方
-Come on! -I want them out of there, guys.
那里怎么回事  请回答
Give an answer, please. What's going on out there?
他叫我这么做的  他叫我这么做的
He made me do it. He talked me into it.
请各位退回来  让空气流通
Please. Please, move back. Please, give these people some air.
退回来
Please, move back.
马丁  只是恶作剧
Martin it's just a hoax.
两个小孩背着假鳍
There are two kids with a cardboard fin.
游客都还好吧
Everyone there okay? Everyone get out of the water all right?
各位  我们开了个鲨鱼鳍的玩笑
Folks, we had some practical joker down there with a fake fin...
鲨鱼
Shark!
是鲨鱼
A shark!
它游进海湾了  鲨鱼游进海湾了
It's going into the pond! Shark in estuary!
又怎么了
Now what?
麦克在水湾里
Michael's in the pond.
鲨鱼在水湾里  快想个办法
Somebody do something! It's in the pond!
鲨鱼在水湾里  水湾里
It's going in the pond! It's in the pond!
-快点弄好  -什么事都弄不好
-Hurry up. Get that done. -I can't do a damn thing.
-把绳子解开  -我正在解
-Get that rope undone. You gotta untangle that up there. -I'm doing it!
小鬼  你们快点行吗
Hey, fellows, Haul in your sheet. Make it fast.
你们还好吗
You guys okay over there?
在水湾里
In the pond!
快来人拿枪拿枪来打它
Somebody get a gun and shoot it!
没人有枪吗
Doesn't anybody have a gun?
-他死了吗  -没有  他受惊了
-Is he dead? -No, he's not. He's in shock.
医生说他没事了  轻微的惊吓  明早就可以回家了
Doctor says he's okay. Mild shock. He can go home in the morning.
-我宝贝儿子还好吗  -我没事
-How's my big kid? -I'm all right.
今晚想我吗  你可以看电视
You gonna miss me tonight? You can watch television.
-要不要我从家里带什么过来  -我的小汽车
-Want anything from home? -My cars.
-要不要冰淇淋  -咖啡
-What about ice cream? -Coffee.
想带他回家吗
Want to take him home?
你是说纽约的家
Like to New York?
不是  这里的家
No. Home, here.
抱歉  我很抱歉  真的
I'm sorry. I'm truly sorry.
你有笔吗  赖利
You got a pen, Larry?
是笔  没错
Yeah, pen, you know.
你得尽力配合
'Cause you're gonna do what you do best.
你在这支票签字  我好去请个雇员
You're gonna sign this voucher so I can hire a contractor.
我不知道我是否有权这么做
I don't know if I can do that without...
我要请昆特来杀鲨鱼
I'm gonna hire Quint to kill the shark.
-八月  -什么
-August? -What?
你胡说什么  夏天快过了
What are you talkin' about? Summer's over.
你是鲨鱼市的市长
You're the Mayor of Shark City.
那些人认为是你要开放海滩的
These people think you want the beaches open.
我是为了本镇的利益着想
I was acting in the town's best interest.
没错  你是为本镇的利益着想
You were acting in the town's best interest.
所以你得做这件事
That's why you're gonna do the right thing.
所以你得签名
That's why you're gonna sign this.
照昆特的条件  付钱给他
And we're gonna pay that guy what he wants.
马丁...
Martin...
我孩子也在海滩玩
My kids were on that beach, too.
签字吧  赖利
Sign it, Larry.
一万元  每天二百  抓到与否照算
$10,000, $200 a day, whether I catch him or not.
没问题
You've got it.
别让市长来烦我  我不想听他那套歪理
Get the Mayor off my back so I don't have more zoning crap.
也没问题
You've got that.
一箱白兰地  午餐由你提供
One case of apricot brandy. And you buy the lunch.
二箱回来再供应晚餐
Two cases. And you get dinner when you get back.
香槟  鹅干酱  伊朗鱼子酱
Champagne, pit de foie gras, Iranian caviar...
别忘了还要彩色电视机
...and don't forget the color TV.
警长  你尝口看看  我自己做的
You try this. Made it myself.
-相当不错  -谢谢
-Pretty good stuff. -Thanks.
敬那些用弓形腿游泳的女人
Here's to swimmin' with bow-legged women.
失陪一下  警长
Excuse me, Chief.
六十岁以下的好手都找不到
Can't get a good man these days. Under 60.
-全在三十五年前就死了  -别喝那种酒
-All gone at least 35 years. -Don't drink that.
昆特先生
Mr. Quint...
昆特先生  你需要一位帮手
Mr. Quint, You'll need an extra hand.
-这位是麦特·胡柏  -我知道他是谁
-This is Matt Hooper. -I know.
-我在讯太平洋号上干过船员  -太平间
-I've crewed three Trans Pacs. -Transplants?
-他是海洋研究所的人  -也在美国实验杯号
-He's from the Oceanographic Institute. -And an America's Cup trial.
胡柏先生  只搭几天游艇  还差的远了
Mr. Hooper. I'm not talkin' about pleasure boatin' or day sailin'.
我要找以航海维生的人  这趟是去捕鲨
I'm talkin' about workin' for a living. I'm talkin' about sharkin'.
我可不是那种普通的捕鱼郎
I'm not talkin' about hookin' some poor dogfish or sand shark.
我的目的是要抓条大白鲨
I'm talkin' about finding a great white.
口气很大  你的口气蛮大的
Porkers? Talkin' about porkers?
你打个缩短节给我看看
Just tie me a sheepshank.
我已经很久没玩这套了
I haven't had to pass basic seamanship in a long time.
你没说想要多短
You didn't say how short you wanted it.
还算可以吧
How's that?
手伸出来
Gimme your hands.
肉白无力
Dogfish?
值五千的鱼网  抓了值二千的鱼
You got a $5,000 net and you got $2,000 worth of fish in it.
等你拉完了网  你这双小白手
Along comes Mr. Whitey. By the time he's finished with that net...
将像剪刀剪破的白纸一样
...it looks like a kiddy's scissors class has cut it up for a paper doll.
你这双小白手只配去数钞票
You got city hands, Mr. Hooper. You been countin' money all your life.
我可不想听黑手阶级的狂言狂语
I don't need this. I don't need this working class hero crap.
你该不会在船上这样对他吧
You're not gonna do this aboard the ship are you, Mr. Quint?
看来我还是自个去吧
Maybe I should go alone.
这件事由我来负责支派
It's my party. It's my charter.
你负责是没错  但是船是我的
Yeah, it's your charter, it's your party. It's my vessel.
你上了我的船
You're on board my vessel...
我就是大副  二副  驾驶  再兼船长
I'm mate, master, pilot and I'm captain.
你要他上来船上当压舱货
I'll take him for ballast, Chief.
我答应你
You got him.
标本瓶  海水染色剂  照明弹  救生衣
Sample bottles, dye marker, flares, safety float,
温度计  鱼枪  半自动枪...
temperature gauge, spear guns, SMG...
你这算什么  半调子的太空人吗
What are you? Some kind of half-assed astronaut?
把这个拿到下面去绑牢
Take that stuff down below and you lash it secure.
老天爷
Jesus H. Christ!
我小的时候
When I was a boy,
每个小孩都想当鱼枪手
every squirt wanted to be a harpooner or a swordfisherman.
你拿这些啥玩意  手提式莲蓬头还是猴子笼
What have you got here? A portable shower or a monkey cage?
-是防鲨笼  -防鲨笼
-An anti-shark cage. -Anti-shark cage?
你要进笼子里
You go inside the cage?
笼子放进海里  你也要下海
Cage goes in the water? You go in the water?
鲨鱼可是也在海里  是咱们的鲨鱼
Shark's in the water. Our shark.
再会吧  美丽的西班牙姑娘
Farewell and adieu to you. Fair Spanish ladies
Farewell and adieu. You ladies of Spain
我已奉命  搭船回波士顿
For we've received orders for to sail back to Boston
这一别  不知何年何月再见
And so never more shall we see you again
-晕船药带了吗  -带了
-Did you take your Dramamine? -Yes.
我在你黑袜子里多放了一副眼镜
I put an extra pair of glasses in your black socks...
还有一瓶鼻药水
...and there's the stuff for your nose.
氧化锌在急救包里
The zinc oxide and Blistex is in the kit.
现在的女孩真他妈的笨  什么事都做不好
Goddamn women today. They can't handle nothin'.
现在的小姐就跟他们的祖母一样笨
Young girls just ain't quite smart like their grandmothers were.
一定是昆特
That's got to be Quint.
-这人真不简单  -我有点怕他
-Colorful, isn't he? -He scares me.
壁炉暂时别用
Don't use the fireplace in the den.
要我怎么跟孩子说
What am I gonna tell the kids?
就说我去钓鱼好了
Tell them I'm going fishing.
别婆婆妈妈的  警长  穷蘑菇什么
Break it up. Will ya. Chief? Daylight's wastin'.
船首  船尾  注意
Front: Bow. Back: Stern.
最好别搞错
Better get it right. Squirt...
否则老子从窗口丢你下海
...or I throw your ass out the little round window on the side.
得了吧  警长  又不是童子军去野餐
This isn't no Boy Scout picnic.
你可没忘记带救生圈
See you got your rubbers.
里面躺着玛莉·李的尸体
Here lies the body of Mary Lee.
死年103岁
Died at the age of 103
连守了15年的贞操
For 15 years she kept her virginity.
在这一带名声清白
Not a bad record for this vicinity"
好了  行政官  系好安全带
All right,commissioner. Fasten your safety belt.
胡柏  如果你看见鲨鱼  就把它吞下去
If you see a shark. Hooper. Swallow.
潜望镜上升  装备好
Up periscope. Rig for depth charge.
准备防火训练
Stand by fire drill.
如何  警长  警长夫人还好吗
How's the Missus, Chief?
如果他们不喜欢你出海  等你回航他们会高兴极了的
If they don't like you goin' out. They'll love you comin' in.
欧卡号
好好保重吧  我们还有五英里才到
Keep that chum line goin'. We got five good miles on it.
-是谁在驾驶  -没有谁  是浪潮
-Who's driving this boat? -Nobody. The tide.
有一次  我抓了一条16英尺长的大鱼
One time. I caught a 16-footer off Montauk.
绑了两个浮桶才制住它  然后拉上船来
Had to stick two barrels in him. Two to wear him down and bring him up.
现在年轻人出海  什么都有
Nowadays, these kids, they take out everything.
雷达  声纳
Radar, Sonar,
还有电动牙刷
Electric toothbrushes.
老天爷
Jesus H. Christ.
警长  最好再丢一个诱饵
Best drop another chum marker.
该死  马丁
Damn it, Martin!
这是压缩空气筒
This is compressed air.
-这算是什么绳结  -你拉错了绳结
-What the hell kind of a knot was that? -You pulled the wrong one.
如果稍有差错  可能会爆炸
You screw around with these tanks. And they're gonna blow up.
你带来的这些行头  都是贵重的好东西
Yeah, that's real fine expensive gear you've brought out here.
就是不知道混蛋鲨鱼  看了会怎样
I don't know what that bastard shark's gonna do with it.
也许会一口吃掉吧  有一次我看到鲨鱼吞下安乐椅
Might eat it, I suppose. Seen one eat a rockin' chair one time.
下次你最好先问我该拉哪条绳子
Next time, you just ask me which line to pull, right?
棕色小鳗鱼钻出动
Little brown eel comes out of the cave...
游进洞口
...swims into the hole...
再出洞口  再进洞口
...comes out of the hole, back into the cave again.
并不太容易吧  警长
It's not too good, is it?
天下无易事  再一次
Nothin's easy, is it? One more time.
我会了
I got it.
-什么  -到我后面来
-What? -Get behind me.
胡柏  退后
Hooper, reverse her!
绳子跑了不少
Takin' a hell of a lot of line.
警长  把勺子拿来  用水浇轮轴
Get the scoop out of the bucket, wet the reel.
胡柏  退后
Reverse her!
头低下来  警长  船开始摇了  到我后面
Duck your head down. We're swingin'. Get behind me again.
水不要了  你想淹死我
No more water. I don't want you to drown me.
胡柏  你这白痴  右舷你没在看吗
Hooper, you idiot. Starboard! Ain't you watchin' it!
胡柏  空档
Hooper, neutral.
这会又跑哪里去了
Where'd he go now?
别想骗我
He ain't foolin' me.
这下又躲到哪去
What's he yankin' on now?
出来试试看
Go on, try it.
很难说  警长  它要么很聪明要么很笨
I don't know, Chief. If he's very smart or very dumb.
它沉到船下面了
Jesus... He's gone under.
它沉到船下面了  我觉得它沉到船下面了
He's gone under the boat. I think he's gone under the boat.
不会这么简单
Yeah, it's too easy.
它是条狡猾的大鱼  跑到船下面去了
He is a smart big fish. He's gone under the boat.
船稳住  我要抓大鱼了
Keep her steady, Now. I got somethin' very big.
我看不见得
I don't think so.
警长  手套戴上
Chief, put your gloves on.
你俩都戴上手套
You put your gloves on, both of you.
它又准备出来了
Getting ready to run out again.
昆特  放了它
Quint, let it go.
你也许在实验室了不得  但在我船上你只是压舱货
You may be big in the lab. But out here you're just cargo.
如果你不想游泳回家  就快给我下来
If you don't want to backstroke home. You get down here.
好吧  听不听随便你
You don't want to listen to me. Don't listen to me.
那不是鲨鱼
It's not a shark.
-铁丝露出来了  -帮我解开
-The wire's showing! -Unbuckle me.
-到另一边去  -若不是鱿鱼就是剑鱼
-Get the other side. -It's a tuna or swordfish.
浪费我们时间
Take this rod.
拉住杆子  胡柏帮警长一下
Give the Chief a hand, will you?
-好  -狗屎
-Right! -Oh, shit!
是马林鱼也可能是黄貂鱼
It's a marlin or a stingray...
但绝对是条大的
...but it's definitely a game fish.
大鱼
Gamin' fish?
马林鱼黄貂鱼  自作聪明的东西
Marlin, stingray bit through this piano wire?
以后少在我面前卖弄  你给我上舰桥上去
Don't you tell me my business again. You get back on the bridge.
昆特  这不能证明什么
Quint, that doesn't prove a damn thing.
胡柏先生  不过有件事可以证明
It proves one thing, Mr. Hooper.
这证明你们这些有钱的大学生
It proves that you wealthy college boys don't have the education enough...
却没有勇气承认自己的错误
...to admit when you're wrong.
这有何意义  不是钩就是绳子
What's the point? Hooks and lines?
没了再挂一个就是了
You lose one. You rig one.
朝东南方全速前进
Twelve minutes, south, southeast, now. Full throttle.
遵命  船长
Aye, aye, Sir.
我的做法你看出来了吧  先把它诱出水面
You see. What I do Chief is trick 'em to the surface.
然后再射它
And then jab at 'em.
我不打算像捉鲶鱼一样用网拖
I'm not gonna haul 'em up like a lot of catfish.
全速前进
Full throttle.
这种窝囊气我快受不了了
I don't have to take this abuse much longer.
你的头在流血了  急救箱在那里
Your head's bleeding. First aid there.
布洛迪  你再放饵
Start that chum line again, will ya?
让胡柏接手
Let Hooper take a turn.
胡柏在开船  警长
Hooper drives the boat.
别自摸了  胡柏  请你慢速前进
Stop playin' with yourself, Hooper. Slow ahead. If you please.
你听到它了  慢速前进
You heard him. Slow ahead.
慢速前进  我也会慢速前进
Slow ahead. I can go slow ahead.
为何不下来  丢这些臭鱼饵
Come on down and chum some of this shit.
你得换条大船才保得住
You're gonna need a bigger boat.
引擎熄掉
Shut off that engine.
有二十英尺长
That's a 20-footer.
二十五英尺  至少三吨重
Twenty-five. Three tons of him.
我们得换大船对吗
We're gonna need a bigger boat, right?
快点下手吧
Gotta get to work.
怎么对付得了  怎么对付呀
How do we handle this?
它在绕船打转看看它多大
Come up front, Martin, I need you. He's circling the boat.
艾米提灯塔呼叫欧卡
Amity Point Light Station to Orca.
This is Amity Point Light Station to Orca.
-快回答  -欧卡  请说
-Come in, Orca. -Orca. Come in.
-布洛迪太太有话要说  -接过来
-I have Mrs. Martin Brody here. -Put her on.
-马丁  快去  -我才不过去
-Come on. Martin! Move! -I'm not goin' out there!
到浮桶旁边  到浮桶末端
Beyond the edge of the barrels. Go to the end of the barrels.
-再过去点  -什么
-Further out. -What?
-再过去  -为什么
-Further out. -Why?
-Go further out. -What for?
请你到甲板旁边行吗
Will you go to the end of the pulpit please?
-什么  -请你到甲板旁边行吗
-What? -Will you go to the end of the pulpit?
-为什么  -我拍照时需要你在前面陪衬
-What for? -I need something in the foreground to give it some scale.
陪衬个屁
Foreground my ass!
你先生正在钓鱼  刚钓到几条纹鱼
Your husband's okay. He's fishin'. He just caught some stripers.
带回去当晚餐  不会太久
We'll bring 'em for dinner. We won't be long.
目前还没有什么发现  完毕
We ain't seen anything yet. Over and out.
-我不要留在那里  -我求求你
-I'm not staying here! -I'm begging you!
该死  来呀  甜心
Goddamn it! Come here. Come here. Darlin'.
警长  我要你到舰桥上  朝前方进行
Chief, I want you up on the bridge. Just take her forward. Steady.
我一辈子也没开过船
I've never steered a boat in my life.
稳着开就好
Just watch my hand. Take her steady.
胡柏先生  把线绑在第一个浮桶上
Mr. Hooper, attach the end of this line to the first keg.
我非先在它头上开一枪不可
I've got to get a good shot at that porker's head.
它来了
He's coming.
胡柏  呆在甲板
Hooper? Get clear of the bow.
胡柏
Hooper?
-绑好  -昆特  轮到你受罪了
-Tied it up, will ya? -Your turn, Quint.
胡柏  你在哪
Hooper, where are you?
胡柏  快点行吗  绑好
Hooper, hurry it up now. Tie it on.
赶紧  它朝着我们来了
Hurry it up. He's comin' straight for us!
-别搞砸了  -别等我
-Don't screw up now. -Don't wait for me.
快  胡柏  快
Come on. Hooper. Come on.
赶紧  快绑
Hurry it up. Tie it on.
开枪昆特  杀了它
Now, now, kill it!
现在
Now!
开枪
Shoot!
时间刚好
Time.
你在干嘛  我没瞄准它的头部
What were you doin'. Anyway? I didn't get a clean shot right in the head.
好吧  看看浮桶什么时候浮起来
All right, let's see how long that barrel takes to bring him up.
再放一个浮桶  我要跟上了
Free another barrel. I'm comin' around again.
-我们现在放弃了是吗  -它带走了一个浮桶
-What do we do now? We're quittin', right? -We got one barrel on him.
我们要待在这里  等它出来
We stay out here until we find him again.
可是我们为何不呼叫他们  派条大船来
We could radio in and get a bigger boat...
警长  别担心
Don't you worry about it, Chief.
不会留疤的
It won't be permanent.
要看永久的伤口吗
You want to see something permanent?
你想感觉一下永久
You want to feel somethin' permanent?
把你的手放在我的帽子下  有一块肿起来的地方
Just put your hand underneath my cap. You feel that little lump?
诺可诺兰斯  波士顿  圣彼得日
Knocko Nolans, St. Paddy's Day, Boston.
我被咬到过
I got that beat.
有条海鳗
It's a moray eel.
咬穿我的潜水装
It bit right through my wet suit.
胡柏  听着
Well, Hoop, now, listen
我不知道  但我参加摔角比赛
I don't know about that, but I entered an arm wrestlin' contest...
在旧金山的奥可酒吧
...in an Oakie bar in San Francisco. See this?
我不能伸直  知道为什么吗
I can't extend that. You know why?
我参加半决赛  庆祝我第三个老婆过世
'Cause in the semi-final celebrating my third wife's demise...
中国佬大汉  拉我过去
...big Chinese fella. He pulled me right over.
看
Look at that.
公牛白眼鲛
That's a bull shark.
它抓我  当我拿样品的时候
He scraped me when I was takin' samples.
给你看样东西  长尾鲛
I got something for you. There's a thresher.
长尾鲛的尾巴
You see that? A thresher's tail.
-长尾鲛  -一种鲨鱼
-Thresher? -It's a shark.
想来一杯吗  敬你的腿
You want a drink? Drink to your leg?
-我敬你的腿  -敬我们的腿
-I'll drink to your leg. -So we drink to our legs.
我这有最炫的
I got the crime de la crime.
这里  等等
Right here. Hold on.
你看见了吗
Here, you see that?
你穿毛衣
You're wearin' a sweater.
这里  玛莉·艾琳·莫夫特
Right there, Mary Ellen Moffit.
她伤了我的心
She broke my heart.
-那是什么  -什么
-What's that one? -What?
那个  在你手臂上
That one, there. On your arm.
是刺青  我清除了
A tattoo. I got that removed.
别告诉我  上面写的是"妈"
Don't tell me. Don't tell me. "Mother."
到底是什么
What is it?
胡柏先生  这是美军印第安纳波里号
Mr. Hooper, that's the U.S.S. Indianapolis.
你上过印第安纳波里号
You were on the Indianapolis?
发生了什么事
What happened?
日本潜水艇在船身打了两枚鱼雷
Japanese submarine slammed two torpedoes into her side, Chief.
我们从提尼安雷岛送原子弹回来
I was comin' back from the island of Tinian to Leyte...
炸广岛的那颗
...just delivered the bomb. The Hiroshima bomb.
一千一百个人掉入海中
1,100 men went into the water.
十二分钟后船也沉了
Vessel went down in 12 minutes.
半小时之内还没事
Didn't see the first shark for about half an hour.
后来就是一条十三英尺的虎鲨  你可知道在海中的感受
Tiger, 13-footer. Know how you know that when you're in the water?
只要看它一眼马上就知道
You tell by lookin' from the dorsal to the tail.
但是我们不知道
Well, We didn't know.
因为这趟任务是个大秘密
Because our bomb mission had been so secret...
没有人发求救信号
...no distress signal had been sent.
一星期后都没人知道我们逾期未归
They didn't even list us overdue for a week.
第一眼就看到鲨鱼  游了过来
Very first light. Sharks come cruisin'...
大伙挤成一团
...so we formed ourselves into tight groups.
就像旧式战争中的方块阵  就和挂历格子一样
Kinda like old squares in a battle like you see on a calendar...
就像滑铁卢战役
...like the Battle of Waterloo.
当时的想法是  万一鲨鱼过来
The idea was. The shark comes to the nearest man...
前面的人就大叫大喊
...and he starts poundin' hollerin' and screamin'.
或许会吓走鲨鱼
Sometimes the shark would go away...
也许根本不会走
...but sometimes he wouldn't go away.
有时候它直瞪着你不放
Sometimes that shark. He looks right into you...
看着你的眼睛
...right into your eyes.
鲨鱼最特别的一点  它有一双痴呆的双眼
You know. A thing about a shark. He's got...
黑色的  像娃娃的眼睛
...lifeless eyes, black eyes. Like a doll's eyes.
它游过来的时候像是死鱼
When he comes at you. He doesn't seem to be livin'...
但是当它咬中你时
...until he bites you.
黑眼翻成白色
Those little black eyes roll over white and then...
然后就是高八度的叫声
...then you hear that terrible high-pitched screamin'.
海水染成红色
The ocean turns red...
混杂着拍水声  呼救声
...in spite of the poundin' and the hollerin'. They all come in.
人就这样被咬成碎片
They rip you to pieces.
天亮之前
You know. By the end of that first dawn...
少了一百人
...we lost 100 men.
我也不知道有多少条鲨鱼  也许一千条
I don't know how many sharks. Maybe 1,000.
平均一小时吃掉六个
I don't know how many men. They averaged six an hour.
星期四早上
On Thursday mornin'.
我发现一位朋友  赫比·罗宾森  克利夫兰人
I bumped into a friend of mine... Herbie Robinson from Cleveland.
棒球手
Baseball player, bosun's mate.
我以为他睡着了
I thought he was asleep.
游过去叫醒他
Reached over to wake him up.
他只是上半段漂在水上
He bobbed up and down in the water just like a kind of top.
下半部全没了
Upended.
从腰以下狠狠地被咬断
He'd been bitten in half. Below the waist.
第五天中午  一架洛克希德·文图拉轰炸机发现了我们
Noon the fifth day. A Lockheed Ventura saw us.
他低空飞行所以看到了我们  是个年轻的飞行员
He swung in low and he saw us. He was a young pilot.
比胡柏先生还年轻  他看到了我们
Younger than Mr. Hooper. He saw us...
他就往低处飞  三小时之后
...and he came in low. And three hours later...
一架大型PBY水上飞机过来接我们
...a big fat PBY comes down and starts to pick us up.
那是我一生中最害怕的时刻
That was the time I was most frightened.
等着轮到我自己
Waitin' for my turn.
之后我再也没有穿过一件救生衣
I'll never put on a life jacket again.
当初落海的是一千一百人
So 1,100 men went into the water...
救回来的只有316人
...316 men come out.
其他人全被鲨鱼吃掉了  1945年6月29日
The sharks took the rest June the 29th, 1945.
反正
Anyway.
谁叫我们送原子弹
We delivered the bomb.
什么声音
What's that?
鲸鱼声
It's a whale.
再见吧
Farewell and adieu to you.
美丽的西班牙女郎
Fair Spanish ladies
再见吧
Farewell and adieu.
美丽的西班牙女郎
You ladies of Spain
请引我走上回家的路
Show me the way to go home
我已疲倦渴望着休息
I'm tired and I want to go to bed
一小时前  喝的酒
I had a little drink about an hour ago
如今已在我脑海中发酵
And it's gone right to my head
不论我流浪到
Wherever I may roam
海角天涯
By land or sea or foam
请引我走上回家的路
Show me the way to go home
我已疲倦渴望着休息
I'm tired and I want to go to bed
一小时前饮的酒  如今已在我脑海中发酵
I had a little drink about a hour ago. And it's gone right to my head
不管我流浪到
Wherever I may roam
海角天涯
On land or sea or foam
你将永远听我唱同一首歌
You can always hear me singing this...
发动引擎
Start the engines.
开动发动
Fire her up!
枪弄好  把火熄掉好吗
Put out the fire, will ya?
-水抽掉  -抽好了
-Pump her out. -Done.
-统统上甲板  -它连灯也吃
-Everybody on deck. -He ate the light.
-这可真好  -对不起
-Terrific. -Excuse me.
昆特  你在干嘛  别浪费时间
Quint, what are you doing? Don't waste your time.
这有什么不对  老天
What's wrong with this?
胡柏  去掌舵
Hooper, take the wheel.
布洛迪你跟着  看好它
Brody, follow that. Watch for him.
你还好吧
You okay?
马丁  你没事吧
Martin, are you okay?
警长  左舷  左手向下拉
Mr. Hooper, more left rudder. Pull your left hand down.
拉不动只能动三寸
I can't. It'll only go about three inches.
给水器中都漂满了油
All of our injectors got scored from the salt water in the fuel.
整条船都快裂了  听听就知道
Yeah, the housing's bent. You can hear it.
再试试左舷好吗
Try the left rudder again.
再左些  再一次
More left. Good. Once again now.
昆特  昆特  昆特  它来了
Quint, there it is.
你说什么  警长
What do you say, Chief?
浮桶浮上来了  在船尾
The barrel is up. It's right in the stern.
看来它就在下面  拿长勾过来
I think he's right under the keg. Grab the boat hook.
昆特  如果无法再接近
Quint, if we can get close enough...
我有样东西可以杀死它
...I've got things on board that'll kill it.
我只是要逗它出来
Just want to goose him up. Come on.
它一跑你就丢绳子  否则手就别要了
When he runs, you drop that rope or you'll lose your hands.
我见过手指连根都断掉
I've seen fingers torn out at the knuckles.
全海面都是指骨  老弟  先给我一下
Whole sea's bones full of 'em. Give it to me a minute.
绳子拉住  别让它耍了
Haul in that line or it'll foul us.
发动引擎
Start the engine.
-你要去哪  -去打个电话
-Where are you goin'? -I'm gonna make a phone call.
喂  喂  欧卡号求救  海岸警卫队
Hello. Hello. Mayday. Orca. Coast Guard?
海岸巡逻队  这是欧卡号  你们听见了吗
Coast Guard. This is the Orca. Do you read me?
海岸巡逻队  这是欧卡号  你们
Coast Guard. This is the Orca. Do you...
抱歉了  警长
Excuse me, Chief.
好极了  这下好极了
That's great. That's just great.
这下子咱们怎么办
Now, where the hell are we, eh?
你有神经病  昆特  你知道吗
You're certifiable. Quint, you know that?
-你有神经病  -是是是
-You're certifiable. -Yeah yeah yeah...
-你有神经病  但我就是要告诉你  -孩子们
-You're certifiable. But I'll tell you this! -Boys.
孩子们  我看它要回来吃午餐了
Oh boys, I think he's come back for his noon feeding.
再帮我钩个浮桶
Hook me up another barrel.
我们去追它
Bring her around after him.
全速前进与它并行
Full throttle. Get me right up alongside of him.
我开不了这么快  船会吃不消
I can't rev it up that high. It's not gonna take it.
左舷五度
Five degrees port.
好方向不变
All right, hold your course.
再左五度
Five degrees port now.
方向不变
Hold your course.
-好快的鱼  -看我的手势
-Fast fish. -Watch my hand.
看着我的手  跟我来
Be sure you watch my hand. Follow me. Follow me.
看着它  右舷  右舷
Lad, you watch him now. Starboard. Starboard.
压下去胡柏
Run him down, Hooper.
左满舵
Hard aport.
看着它  右舷  右舷
Watch him. Starboard. Starboard.
真不敢相信  两个浮桶  它还沉得下去
I can't believe it. Two barrels and he's going down again.
真不可思议
It's incredible.
-又浮上来了  -现在怎么办
-They're up again! -Now what?
我们为何不把鲨鱼引到岸上
Why don't we lead the shark into shore
总比让它引到外海好
instead of him leading us out to sea?
拿两根杆子来
Grab a couple of poles.
抓稳要转了
Hang on now. We're going around.
换成右舷  慢慢来
Into starboard. Easy.
再回原方向  你看着木桶
I'm gonna back her off now. Keep a watch on it, boys. Watch him.
好了  各位  钩回来
All right, gentlemen, snag them.
现在绑在船首钩上
Now then tie them to the stern cleats.
布洛迪  绳头绑在钩上
Brody, bring your end around the cleat.
对  打个死结
That's right. It'll lock itself off.
布洛迪  别拉到他
Give him room, Brody.
别太靠近绳子
Stay clear of the line.
小心  别靠近
Watch it. Stand clear.
别靠近挂钩
Stand away from those stern cleats.
镇上有个计程车司机
Back home we got a taxidermy man.
等我把鲨鱼捉回去  他一定心脏病发
He gonna have a heart attack when he sees what I brought him.
快退回来钩子松了
Throttle back. You're losing the cleats.
瞧瞧  老天  两个都松了
My God. This one, too. They're both going.
它一直跟着绳子往上吃
He's eating his way through that line.
对  它冲着我们来
He's working his way right up to us.
昆特  快
Quint!
昆特
Come on, Quint. Hurry!
别挡路
Out of my way.
小心
Watch it.
解开钩子要拔掉了
Untie this. He'll pull out the transom.
快点  我们用另一条线牵着它
Make it fast! We got another line in him!
没办法  它想逃
I can't. It's trying to run.
快拉呀  狗杂碎
Pull, you son of a bitch!
希望你的背断掉
I hope your back breaks!
拉使劲拉
Go on. Pull your bloody heart out.
解开
Tie him off! Do it. Tie him off!
不可能  不可能
It's impossible! It's impossible!
绳子太紧了  它在拉我们
The line is too tight. He's towing us!
我们要松开  不然它会把钩子拉掉
Cut him loose or he'll pull the transom off!
撑不住了  快切断  钩子要掉了
We're breaking up! Cut it, man. It's coming off!
拿东西来切断
The ax! Get the ax!
快撑不住了  快撑不住了
We're breaking us! We're breaking up!
-切  快切  -当心你们的手
-Cut it! Cut it! -Watch your hands!
-抓紧  -快切啊昆特  我抓不住了
-Come on! Hold it! -Cut it! I can't hold it!
切啊  快切
Cut it! Cut it!
三个浮桶它沉不下去
He can't stay down with three barrels on him.
三个  它别做梦了
Not with three barrels. He can't.
我们怎么办
What about us?
把你前面的泵拿来
Get the pump out of the locker in front of you, will you?
我们会沉下去
We're gonna sink, aren't we?
胡柏  看着浮桶
Keep an eye on the barrels.
快点抽  警长
Pump it out, Chief.
是不是要下沉
Starting to go under.
不可能三个桶它没办法
He can't with three barrels on him. Not with three he can't.
你以前碰过这么大的吗
You ever have one do this before?
没有
No.
它追我们真不敢相信
He's chasin' us. I don't believe it.
我要拉它到浅水去
I'm gonna draw him into the shallows.
我要拉它去浅滩让它死
Draw him into the shallow water. I'm gonna draw him in and drown him.
-我们前进  布洛迪  -谢谢上帝
-We're headin' in, Brody. -Thank Christ!
-你以前见过大白鲨吗  -没有
-You ever had a great white do that? -No.
我们还要走多远
How far do we have to go?
别让船吃不消
Don't put that much pressure on it.
-该死  -闭嘴  给我回去看着
-Goddamn it. -Shut up. Get back there.
抓稳
Hold on.
再会吧  美丽的西班牙女郎
Farewell and adieu to you. Fair Spanish ladies
Farewell and adieu. You ladies of Spain
因为我已奉命  即将返回波士顿
For we received order for to sail back to Boston
白痴  你会烧坏引擎
You idiot. You burned out the bearings.
好了  停船  停船
All right stop the boat. Stop the boat. Stop it.
胡柏  你们带这些东西  是干什么用的
Hoop, What exactly can you do with these things of yours?
在里面装二十CC的硝酸盐
I think I can pump 20 cc of strychnine nitrate into him.
如果靠近一点的话
If I can get close enough.
就可以打进它的体内
Get this little needle through his skin?
不  我做不到
No, I can't do that.
但如果距离够近  我想由笼子里打入它的嘴中
If I can get him close to the cage. I can get him in the mouth.
-鲨会撕烂你的笼子  -你还有更好的意见吗
-That shark'll rip that cage to pieces. -You got any better suggestions?
-慢点  -慢点
-Easy. -Easy.
竖起来
Up she goes.
我不用鱼枪
Ain't got no spit.
我没下去前别让它靠近
Try and keep him off me until I'm lower.
好了  我准备好了
Okay, okay, I'm ready.
把他拉上来该死
Bring him up. Goddamn it. Bring him up now!
把他拉上来
Pull it up.
拉他上来
Pull it.
Come on, Quint. Bring him in.
掉下来了
It's giving way.
装上绳索  装上绳索
Rig something! Rig something!
拉住了吗  好的
Got it? All right.
上来了
It's comin'.
慢点
Slow down
Slower
好的  来
All right, come on.
来呀  给我看钢桶
Show me the tank.
炸死你
Blow up!
笑吧  你这...
Smile. You son of a bitch!
船长呢
Quint?
他没熬过来
No.
能到那边去吗
Can we get in on those?
今天星期几
What day is this?
星期三  应该是星期二
It's Wednesday. It's Tuesday. I think.
我们是顺流
I think the tide's with us.
继续踢
Keep kicking.
我以前一直讨厌海水
I used to hate the water.
我可以想像原因
I can't imagine why.